CHRIS HENRICK

WEB DEVELOPER AT RADISH LAB

Brooklyn, NY chrishenrick@gmail.com http://chrishenrick.com https://github.com/clhenrick

Summary

Chris recently completed an MFA in Design and Technology at Parsons School of Design in New York City where he broadened his technical skills in web-development and web-design with a focus on user experience, data visualization, and story telling with interactive web-mapping. Following Parsons he began working for Radish Lab as a web-developer and data / mapping specialist where he helps build interactive data visualizations for non-profits and cultural institutions. Prior to that he assisted CartoDB with improving their internal geocoder for their open-source web-mapping and GIS platform. He has also worked as a cartographer and GIS specialist at Avalon Travel Publishing in Berkeley, CA and as a GIS intern at GreenInfo Network in San Francisco, CA. Additionally Chris has performed consultant work for the Oakland Museum of California, as well as for independent and self-published authors. His undergraduate degree is in Geography and Urban Studies, from Temple University in Philadelphia, PA. In his spare time Chris also helps organize and facilitate Maptime-NYC, a volunteer group dedicated to educating non-experts about open-source GIS, cartographic design, and interactive web-mapping.

Experience

Radish Lab Web Developer

05 / 2015 - Present

Currently assisting Radish Lab with developing interactive data visualizations using technologies such as D3 JS, CartoDB JS, and Node JS as well as general web development using Wordpress and front end technologies such as HTML, CSS, Javascript.

Chris Henrick Cartography Cartographer

06 / 2010 - Present

Currently consulting in the field of digital cartography and geospatial data visualization. Specializing in using various geospatial data formats, open-source GIS software, web-mapping libraries, and professional graphics editing programs to create clean, legible, and stylistically appropriate map graphics. Former clients include Rebecca Solnit, The Oakland Museum of California, Avalon Travel Publishing, as well as academics and self published authors.

CartoDB Intern

03 / 2014 - 09 / 2014

Assisted CartoDB with testing, documenting, educating users and promoting their cloud based data mapping and spatial data analysis tool CartoDB.

Worked on improving CartoDB's internal geocoder using open data and PostgreSQL with

Parsons School of Design at The New School

07 / 2014 - Present

Teacher Assistant

Assisting with developing curriculum and teaching front-end web and javascript programming to the incoming class of Parsons' M.S. in Data Visualization program. While an MFA student I was a TA for a BFA creative code class.

InsideSchools.org Research Assistant

01 / 2014 - 06 / 2014

Assisted the non-profit Inside Schools with augmenting their robust NYC public-school search web-application with a dynamic web-mapping application that utilizes Leaflet JS and base-map tiles from MapBox.

Avalon Travel Publishing Cartographer

01 / 2012 - 05 / 2013

Assisted Avalon Travel Publishing's cartography team with creating new maps and updating existing maps for their printed and ebook travel guide series which include titles such as Moon Handbooks, Rick Steve's, and Let's Go. Performed additional map design for independent publishers that belong to the Perseus Books Group such as Westview Press and Nation Books.

Primary responsibilities included working with the cartography editors to render and update 30 - 60 maps per book depending on a book's geographic scope. This tended to be 3 - 5 books per week depending on the production schedule.

Designed and implemented a workflow for incorporating spatial data into map design through the use of QGIS, GDAL/OGR2OGR, Natural Scene Designer, MAPublisher, and Adobe Illustrator.

Helped design and implement a schema to store geocoded point of interest data. Wrote scripts to help automate repetitive cartographic design tasks using the Scriptographer plugin for Adobe Illustrator.

Organized a GIS data server.

GreenInfo Network Cartographer Intern

01 / 2011 - 06 / 2011

Assisted GreenInfo Network with cartographic layout and edits including production maps for Save the Redwoods League, Sustainable Conservation, and other clients. Utilized Arc GIS 9.3 / 10 to edit, analyze, and implement GIS into refined cartographic styles that conformed to clients' objectives and identity.

GreenInfo Network GIS Analyst Intern

06 / 2010 - 10 / 2010

Assisted the GreenInfo Network with it's mission of providing GIS analysis, cartography, and data visualization for non-profit organizations in the San Francisco bay area,

California, and North America. Projects worked on included updating the California Protected Areas Database (CPAD), GIS analysis of current and historical habitat for the rare Black -Backed Woodpecker, map editing for the Protect Wild California atlas, and other administrative duties.

ASIAN Inc.

11 / 2009 - 06 / 2010

Volunteer GIS Analyst

ASIAN Inc. is a community and economic development non-profit that helps promote housing and business opportunities for Asian Americans and other minority groups in the San Francisco bay area. They are also one of the Census Information Centers in the SF bay area, a go-to place for people to retrieve census information including updates for the 2010 decennial census. I contributed work to various projects for the organization that utilize census demographic data and GIS analysis and data visualization to help promote their goals and mission statement.

Steve Spindler Cartography Assistant Cartographer

06 / 2009 - 11 / 2009

Assisted a professional cartographer in creating print maps for cross-state bicycle touring routes in Pennsylvania.

The Delaware Valley Regional Planning Commission 01 / 2008 - 07 / 2008

Planning Intern

Assisted the Office of Transit, Pedestrian and Bicycle Planning in implementing projects related to non-motorized transportation planning in the metropolitan Philadelphia area. Participated in tasks such as survey field-work, road safety audits, data entry, bicycle route mapping, power point presentations, and other operational tasks as determined by the office manager.

Education

Parsons School of Design Master of Fine Arts (MFA) , Design and Technology

2013 - 2015

Design & Technology Bootcamp Teaching Fellow, Summer of 2014

University of California, Berkeley Certificate Program, Graphic Design

2009 - 2010

Temple University B.A., Geography and Urban Studies

2005 - 2008

Member of Gamma Theta Upsilon, National Honors Society for Geography Recipient of the Henry N. Michael Prize in Geography and Urban Studies

Honors

- New Challenge 2015 winner; recipient of \$5,000 grant.
- Gamma Theta Upsilon, National Honors Society for Geography.
- Recipient of the Henry N. Michael Prize in Geography and Urban Studies.

Interests

cartography, web-mapping, GIS, graphic design, open-source software, open-data, data visualization, typography

Associations

NACIS, Temple University Alumni, OpenStreetMap US, Maptime / Maptime NYC

Languages

• English

• Spanish

Publications

BAAMA Journal

05 / 2013

Bay Area Automated Mapping Association · Authors: Chris Henrick ·

http://www.baama.org/journal

My map Oakland: Then and Now (created for the Oakland Museum of CA) is featured in the Spring 2013 Volume 7 Issue 1 of the Bay Area Automated Mapping Association's (BAAMA) Journal, a biannual publication that serves to highlight San Francisco Bay Area geospatial businesses, agencies, people, technology, applications, projects, and maps.

Skills

- Cartography
- D3.js • Github
- PostGIS
- CSS
- Illustrator
- OS X

- Web Mapping
- Python
- Git
- Tile Mill
- MAPublisher
- Photoshop

- · Node.js
- JavaScript
- QGIS
- HTML ArcGIS
- InDesign
- Geospatial Data Abstraction Library (GDAL)